

AMAL SURENDRAN B. TECH, MS

PROFILE

A qualified Mechanical Engineer with Master graduation in Industrial Management, also having 9 years of experience in India and Sweden in the Engineering and Management field. I possess strong multi-tasking skills, with ability to adapt and manage several projects and schedules effectively. I hereby looking for a great opportunity in an immense reputed organization to enhance my career

CONTACT

amalsurendran122@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/amalsurend ran20

Mobile: +919995815925

Whatsapp: +46767404044

ADDRESS

Kalathilpadam House, Mambra Road, Chalikkavattom, Vennala P.O Kochi, Kerala, India PIN: 682028

EXPERIENCE

ASST.MANAGER – MARKETING (MEP) HENRY & FARAD PVT LTD, KERALA INDIA

MARCH 2023 – PRESENT

- Meeting with architects, civil engineers, and clients for the product presentation. Conducting detailed study of the construction site.
- Project planning and management. Preparation of material cost and work schedule
- Developing maintenance standards and providing schedules programs and guidance to service and maintenance team in case of unexpected mechanical failures
- Evaluate projects to ensure compliance with standards for mechanical systems

MANAGER – MARKETING & SALES, JJ INDUSTRIES, KERALA INDIA

MAY 2022 - JANUARY 2023

- Conducting marketing for the product Neurapanel and preparing the sales strategies for the same.
- Meeting with architects, civil engineers, and clients for the product presentation. Conducting detailed study of the construction site.
- Estimation and bidding for commercial and private buildings for Civil related works
- Project planning and management. Preparation of material cost and work schedule.
- Developing maintenance standards and providing schedules
- Programs and guidance to the new market vendors and suppliers with technical assistance
- Evaluation of the completed project and its report preparation

RIDER CAPTAIN, FOODORA AB, SWEDEN

OCTOBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2022

- Prepare daily, weekly, and monthly report of 40 delivery riders
- Detailed analysis of the past performances of the riders
- Approval for sickness and other emergency absences

PERSONAL PROFILE

DOB: 20-02-1992

Sex: Male

Nationality: Indian

Marital status: Single

BRANDS HANDLED

ETA GENERAL

CARRIER

SAMSUNG

HITACHI

DAIKIN

AREA OF INTEREST
MEP ENGINEERING WORKS

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT

AGILE PROJECT MANAGEMENT

AUTOMOBILE ENGINEERING

INTERESTS

READING

TRAVELLING

MUSIC

LANGUAGES KNOWN

ENGLISH

SWEDISH

MALAYALAM

HINDI

TAMIL

Hiring and training for the onboard employees

SALES ENGINEER - MEP, HENRY & FARAD PVT LTD, KERALA INDIA

JULY 2017 - JULY 2019

- Meeting with architects, civil engineers, and clients for the product presentation. Conducting detailed study of the construction site.
- Project Tendering: Estimation and bidding for commercial and private buildings for HVAC and related works
- Preparation of rate charts for HVAC related materials and machineries and updating the same in monthly basis
- Design machines, components tools and fixtures according to the site condition.
- Project planning and management. Preparation of material cost and work schedule
- Developing maintenance standards and providing schedules programs and guidance to service and maintenance team in case of unexpected mechanical failures
- Ensure that all mechanical site activities are conducted under controlled conditions as per shop drawings, method statements, specifications and work plan
- Evaluate projects to ensure compliance with standards for mechanical systems

PROJECT/SALES ENGINEER (HVAC) – TECHNO GREEN MEP SOLUTIONS, KERALA INDIA

AUGUST 2013 - MAY 2017

- Meeting with architects, civil engineers, and clients for the product presentation. Conducting detailed study of the construction site.
- Project Tendering: Estimation and bidding for commercial and private buildings for HVAC and related works
- Preparation of rate charts for HVAC related materials and machineries and updating the same in monthly basis
- Preparation of standard operating procedures for both office and project teams
- Project planning and management. Preparation of material cost and work schedule

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Ability to work under pressure

Knowledge of technical diagrams

Multitasking

Flexibility and adaptability

Hard working

Highly organized

Creative thinking

Agile project management

Business development

Goal oriented

- Supervision, monitoring and inspection of the installation and commissioning of mechanical systems at construction sites
- Developing maintenance standards and providing schedules programs and guidance to service and maintenance team in case of unexpected mechanical failures
- Ensure that all mechanical site activities are conducted under controlled conditions as per shop drawings, method statements, specifications, and work plan
- Evaluate projects to ensure compliance with standards for mechanical systems

EDUCATION

MASTER'S IN INDUSTRIAL MANAGEMENT (MS)

HALMSTAD UNIVERSITY, SWEDEN (2019 – 2020)

THESIS: STATUS OF THE TECHNOLOGY OF WATERLESS TOILETS

SYSTEMS: AN INTERNATIONAL OUTLOOK

BACHELOR'S IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (B. TECH)

MAHATMA GANDHI UNIVERSITY, KERALA, INDIA (2009 – 2013)

TECHNICAL QUALIFICATION

- Completed professional HVAC training program from TAIBA EBGINEERING CONSULTANTS in 2013
- Completed professional FIRE FIGHTING training program from TAIBA EBGINEERING CONSULTANTS in 2013

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Product management
- Strategic planning
- Visualization and Prototyping
- Research and Development

DECLARATION

I ASSURE THAT THE ABOVE FURNISHED INFORMATION IS TRUE TO ACCORDING TO THE BEST OF MY KNOWLEDGE AND BELIEF

01/04/2023

AMAL SURENDRAN